<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Chris Guiterman</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Chris Guiterman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/avatar.jpg</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/project/na-fire-synthesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/na-fire-synthesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;synthesizing-the-north-american-fire-scar-record&#34;&gt;Synthesizing the North American Fire Scar Record&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly 2000 tree-ring fire history sites have been sampled over the last 40 years, and yet few have attempted to consolodate, organize, and understand this incredible resource. Ellis Margolis and I are leading a group of over 30 scientists to synthesize the record of historical fire regimes across the North American continent. The project is in its infancy, but already we&amp;rsquo;ve added more than 1000 sites to the data set of publicly available tree-ring fire history collections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://chguiterman.github.io/NAFireHistory/map.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://chguiterman.github.io/NAFireHistory/map.html&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for collaborators and data contributors. If you would like to join us, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/project/sw-fire-synthesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/sw-fire-synthesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this project we are seeking to better understand - and highlight - the spatial and temporal diversity of historical fire regimes in Arizona and New Mexico as reconstructed from tree rings. Currently, we are examining 414 sites including 5,039 trees, and 37,220 fire scars (and the network is growing). We have found substantial diversity in fire activity, fire seasonality, and fire-climate relationships.
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/fire-years.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
This project is a collaboration with Ellis Margolis, Steven Malevich, Tom Swetnam, Don Falk, Chris Baisan, Erica Bigio, Peter Fule, and Peter Brown.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/project/dfoliatr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/dfoliatr/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
